TSINAT ZEREE

Oakland, CA C: (510) 387-9858 | tsinatzeree@gmail.com

Website:-http://www.tsinatzeree.com/ GitHub:- https://github.com/tsinat

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with emphasis on the Frontend with hands on experience building REST-ful + SPA and Isomorphic applications using JavaScript and other frameworks and libraries. I am quick to adopt to new environment and hungry for new challenges and solving problems on a daily basis.

KEY SKILLS

- Web Technologies: JavaScript, Angular, React, Redux, Express, Mongoose, HTML5, CSS3, SASS
- Database: NoSQL, MongoDB, SQL, MySQL
- Tools: Webpack, Babel, Grunt, Gulp, Git
- Exposure: Java, Python, ionic, Karma, LESS
- Testing: chai, mocha, Jasmine

Sample code

• **GetMentor:** https://github.com/tsinat/getTutor (ReactJS, Redux, Express, MongoDB)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Employer: Coding House — Fremont, CA

Apr 2016 to Dec 2016

Title: Full Stack Developer

- Full Stack development using Node.js, Express, React, Angular, MongoDB and consume internal and external RESTful APIs
- Designed and developed custom and social media authentication with multiple level of authorizations
- Developed and maintained a reusable components repository.

Freelance: — Asmara, Eritrea

Nov 2013 to Jul 2015

Worked with multiple agencies and studios to develop dozens of custom, WordPress and Joomla solutions for their clients ranging from personal blogs to marketing agencies

Employer: Ministry of Education-- Asmara, Eritrea

Nov 2011 to Oct 2013

Title: Frontend Developer

- Transitioned the team from waterfall life cycle to agile development methodologies which cuts development cost by 15%
- Designed development of presentation layers using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery and developed custom user specific plugins
- Collaborate with other departments by providing important customer feedback, processimprovement suggestions which cut the time it took to process applications by 40%

Employer: ESMG — Asmara, Eritrea
Title: Frontend Developer

May 2011 to Sep 2011

- Engaged in responsive website design and development of Cross-Browser compatible and standards-compliant websites using HTML5/CSS/JavaScript
- Migrated content from existing website to a new, database driven website,
- Developed in house Content Management System which cut the work force by 20%

Education

B.Sc. of Science in Computer Science
Eritrea Institute of Technology (EIT) -- Mainefhi, Eritrea

2011